<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz>
  <question id="1">
    <title>Network Security Basics</title>
    <text>What does the acronym "CIA" stand for in information security?</text>
    <options>
      <option key="A">Central Intelligence Agency</option>
      <option key="B">Confidentiality, Integrity, Availability</option>
      <option key="C">Computer Information Access</option>
      <option key="D">Certified Information Analyst</option>
    </options>
    <correct>B</correct>
    <explanation>The CIA triad is a fundamental concept in information security that represents three core principles:

**Confidentiality**: Ensuring that information is accessible only to those authorized to have access. This involves protecting data from unauthorized disclosure through encryption, access controls, and authentication.

**Integrity**: Maintaining the accuracy and completeness of data. This means protecting information from unauthorized modification, deletion, or corruption through checksums, digital signatures, and version control.

**Availability**: Ensuring that information and resources are accessible to authorized users when needed. This involves maintaining system uptime, preventing denial-of-service attacks, and having proper backup and recovery procedures.

These three principles form the foundation of most security policies and frameworks.</explanation>
  </question>
  
  <question id="2">
    <title>Encryption Methods</title>
    <text>Which type of encryption uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?</text>
    <options>
      <option key="A">Asymmetric encryption</option>
      <option key="B">Public key encryption</option>
      <option key="C">Symmetric encryption</option>
      <option key="D">Hash encryption</option>
    </options>
    <correct>C</correct>
    <explanation>**Symmetric encryption** uses the same key for both encryption and decryption operations. This is also known as private key encryption or secret key encryption.

**Characteristics of symmetric encryption:**

- **Speed**: Generally faster than asymmetric encryption
- **Key sharing challenge**: Both parties must securely share the same key
- **Scalability issues**: Each pair of communicating parties needs a unique shared key
- **Examples**: AES, DES, 3DES, Blowfish

**Why other options are incorrect:**

- **Asymmetric encryption**: Uses different keys (public/private key pairs)
- **Public key encryption**: Another term for asymmetric encryption
- **Hash encryption**: Hashing is a one-way function, not encryption that can be decrypted</explanation>
  </question>
  
  <question id="3">
    <title>Firewall Types</title>
    <text>What type of firewall operates at the application layer and can inspect the content of data packets?</text>
    <options>
      <option key="A">Packet filtering firewall</option>
      <option key="B">Stateful inspection firewall</option>
      <option key="C">Application layer firewall (Proxy firewall)</option>
      <option key="D">Circuit-level gateway</option>
    </options>
    <correct>C</correct>
    <explanation>An **Application layer firewall** (also called a proxy firewall) operates at Layer 7 of the OSI model and can inspect the actual content of data packets, not just headers.

**Key features:**

- **Deep packet inspection**: Can examine application-specific data
- **Protocol awareness**: Understands specific application protocols (HTTP, FTP, SMTP, etc.)
- **Content filtering**: Can block based on content, not just addresses and ports
- **Proxy functionality**: Acts as an intermediary between clients and servers

**Comparison with other firewall types:**

- **Packet filtering**: Only examines headers (Layer 3/4)
- **Stateful inspection**: Tracks connection states but limited content inspection
- **Circuit-level gateway**: Works at the session layer, doesn't inspect application data

**Use cases**: Web content filtering, malware detection, data loss prevention</explanation>
  </question>
</quiz>
